<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Swim Preceptors]]></title><description><![CDATA[Swim Preceptors]]></description><link>https://www.swimpreceptors.com/blog-1</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 13:07:20 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.swimpreceptors.com/blog-feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[5 BENEFITS KIDS GET FROM SWIM CLASSES]]></title><description><![CDATA[Irresistible BENEFITS that will make you send your kids to learn-to-swim classes NOW! Is your child bored at home? or is he/she spending...]]></description><link>https://www.swimpreceptors.com/post/5benefitsfromswimming</link><guid isPermaLink="false">633174977ddab563bce5cc61</guid><pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 07:51:33 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c7eb0d_f3cdc7cc6b3b48ba96a4ff51b7c1a75a~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>swimpreceptors</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Irresistible BENEFITS that will make you send your kids to learn-to-swim classes NOW!</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c7eb0d_f3cdc7cc6b3b48ba96a4ff51b7c1a75a~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Is your child bored at home? or is he/she spending too much time on the TV? or is he/she playing too much? If the answer is yes to any of these questions, we got the perfect solution for you.......</p>

<p>Start Swimming!</p>

<p>Swimming is an essential life skill that everyone should know, regardless of age. Not just that, learning how to swim also gives the young a lot of benefits, not just physically, but on their soft skills as well. The benefits of learning how to swim, and swimming itself, has way too many benefits for a young singaporean kid to have, that could really set the stage for a bright future!</p>

<p>Let's dig into some of the benefits of what learn-to-swim classes can do for your child!</p><hr><p><strong>#1 Swimming Can Help Develop Social Skills</strong></p>

<p>You might be wondering, how do kids socialize if they are swimming, faced down into the water? Well, although that might be true, during swimming lessons, kids are tasked with different group activities which allows the coach to communicate with them, and forces the kids in the class to interact with one another to get the job done. </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c7eb0d_f55a00e4bbc942c18c75ae99eb00f338~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>In a group class setting, kids in a group classes also learn to communicate to each other by encouraging one another, and respecting one another. Kids learn how to express their feelings towards others. </p>

<p>All these may not seem like much, but the social skill they develop and set the stage for a positive interpersonal relationship, which would help kids greatly as they grow.</p>

<p>In time to come, you will realise that your kids can be well-versed in conversations, with an outgoing personality which allows they to speak their mind, but also at the same time be mindful of what they say given the situation. </p>


<p><strong>#2 Swimming Improves Motor Skills</strong></p>

<p>Motor skills are functions that involve specific movement of the body which requires the nervous system, muscles and brain to work together to perform a certain task. Just as how in-flexibility occurs as we grow older, kids in general, tend to have a larger range of motion in their limbs which allows them to do more physical movements, which is easier to learn more and/or different motor skills.</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c7eb0d_ebc0aaf7f6fc47668224eebeecd50d54~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>A good example of a motor skill would be the basic hand-eye coordination. Through learning how to swim and routinely swimming, kids can find that they are better able to use their hands to complete a task. </p>

<p>As kids grow older, they progress to face more challenging tasks, which will require different motor skills. Simple motor skills, like using a scissors, or colouring on a template, are all stepping stones for kids to handle more complicated tasks. </p>

<p>You will find that with swimming, your kids will have learnt a lot more different motor skills than his/her peers, and that they can even pick up new motor skills faster than their peers.</p>



<p><strong>#3 Swimming Helps Overcome Water Phobia</strong></p>


<p>The fear of water, or commonly known as Aquaphobia, is very common in young children as they have little to no experience with water. As shown in recent studies, Aqua phobia has been the cause of many drowning cases, in which, 54% of them have led to it being fatal in kids aged 1-4 years old. </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c7eb0d_b96586378f2a4ea390acf0ce485eb456~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Water Phobia can be caused by many different reasons. Due to the fear of water these children have, it can cause panic, which would result in drowning cases. </p>

<p>There is no doubt that swimming lessons can remove the fear of water in children. However, it also teaches them how to react and behave in the various situations that can happen while being in a water body. A research by Griffith University, in Australia, has found that kids, aged 3-5, who have learnt how to swim, reduced the risk of drowning by 88%. </p>

<p>The water confidence your kids will have through learning how to swim will be useful life long survival skill. </p>




<p><strong>#4 Swimming Builds Confidence In Kids</strong></p>

<p>Can you recall the feeling when you accomplish a 2.4KM run, and you feel so satisfied that makes you want to run more the next time? that is the increase self esteem kids feel with each compliment from coaches and/peers after they complete a certain task. This feeling also serves as a form of encouragement which can make them feel more confident to face the next, more difficult, task.</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c7eb0d_78aee8e8cb784edbb6990c726a8f38a4~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Confidence is not just a personality, but also a character. Like every character in a kid, it has been either taught, and/or inculcated since young. At an early age in life, being able to learn how to swim is the best way to build their confidence. </p>



<p>You might ask, why is it important for kids to have confidence? Well, confidence sets the stage of your child's mindset, as to how they perceive difficult tasks being handed to them. Being confident, helps sets a positive and resilient mindset to tackle the task head on. </p>

<p>Moreover, think about it, imagine the amount of confidence built in your kid from learning how to swim! It will give him/her a very good foundation to build more confidence to do greater things in life! Can you imagine how much more your kid can achieve with this new found confidence? </p>


<p><strong>#5 Swimming Enhances Cognitive Functions</strong></p>

<p>Yes! Swimming does make kids smarter (actually does). A very important attribute for a Singaporean child as they grow up in a highly competitive environment with a fast-paced lifestyle. </p>

<p>Swimming lessons allow kids to engage in critical thinking through the different movements or activities being demonstrated. Kids are forced to understand how the mechanics of swimming works. </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c7eb0d_2e80e5a000c246299b1af4f9f2972e02~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Statistics have shown that children aged 3-5 who have been attending swimming lessons are months ahead in their cognitive functions as compared to children who have not attended swimming lessons on a regular basis. In another study, it was also shown that kids who had swimming lessons when they were younger, score academically better compared to those kids who did not.</p>
<hr><p><strong>In Conclusion......</strong></p>

<p>Learning how to swim is a life skill which everyone should know. Better yet, it provides many many other benefits to a child as we talked about above. </p>

<p>Swimming provides a holistic develop for a Singaporean child as they grow up in a highly competitive academic society. </p>

<p>In Swim Preceptors, we inculcate activities that links what kids will learn in school as well as skills they need to learn how to swim. Even after learning the basic strokes in swimming, we encourage parents to send kids to competitive swimming or try learning a new sport. </p>

<p>So, if you want your kid to excel in life, start them to learn how to swim! There is literally zero downsides and all the upsides! Alright, that's enough of hard selling. </p>

<p>Okay, for real, starting your kid for swimming classes might just be a good idea..... See you in the pool! :)</p>
 ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why choose private lessons instead of group lessons?]]></title><description><![CDATA[OUR ADVOCACY As Swim Preceptors is an advocate of refining the way we teach our preceptees, we encourage our clients and preceptees to...]]></description><link>https://www.swimpreceptors.com/post/why-choose-private-lessons-instead-of-group-lessons</link><guid isPermaLink="false">625128c0b045229cc16bef0e</guid><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 06:20:24 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c7eb0d_0c1ae06b450e45ca9e9a4bce1fd1272f~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>swimpreceptors</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c7eb0d_0c1ae06b450e45ca9e9a4bce1fd1272f~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>OUR ADVOCACY</strong></p>

<p>As Swim Preceptors is an advocate of refining the way we teach our preceptees, we encourage our clients and preceptees to join our 1 to 1 classes with our preceptors, instead of group classes. </p>

<p>Come take a look below as to why we advise 1 to 1 classes! Don't miss out!</p>

<p>While we still do offer, group classes, we would encourage preceptees who are in group classes to have a relationship with the other preceptee(s), either as a friend, relative or sibling. This is to have a better class dynamic between preceptor and preceptees to have the most effective learning possible. </p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c7eb0d_bfe22c67f82d4b9ab86cfece224101fb~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>#QUALITY</strong></p>
<p>Private, 1 to 1 lessons offer tremendous amount of benefit, including lesson quality. Quality of lesson does not equate to preceptees learning of to swim in the shortest time possible. However, it is the process of learning while keeping an interest of learning “how to swim” alive in each preceptee. So that when each lessons comes, they are more receptive to learning and looks forward to learning more.</p>

<p>Each preceptee all have a different learning ability, on how fast they learn, on how the learn best, how receptive they can be to certain exercises and activities. Our Preceptors adapts to each preceptee by catering specific activities and exercises for preceptees to be able to learn efficiently.</p>

<p>Coming from a background that treats each preceptee based on thier their own capabilities and personality, we strongly encourage each preceptee to learn at their own pace. This also helps preceptors to adapt to their learning style so that we can make each preceptees learning a more fruitful one. </p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c7eb0d_d292748eef91459ba821d971dd7344ae~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>#SAFETY</strong></p>
<p>Being around water can be dangerous, being in a water body, be it the pool or the beach, there will always be potential hazards. Swim Preceptors would want all our preceptees to be safe, and to practice safe measures when conducting lessons as to minimize safety breach. That is why we have a swim module on water safety as part of our curriculum. </p>

<p>1 to 1 classes allows preceptees to have preceptors undivided attention and can be looked after at all times. As we promote and encourage 1 to 1 classes, we still offer group classes of a maximum of 4. Why 4 you may wonder. Sometimes, in a big group class (more than 4) kids can get restless and start wandering around in the pool and leave the line of sight of instructors. This then turns into a danger as the kid might slip and fall without anyone knowing or go into the deeper end of the pool where they would have nothing to support themselves. 
 </p>
<p>1 to 1 classes Also helps to better manage preceptees expectations on themselves. When in a group, preceptees tend to compare to their friends who are in the same class as them. While we encourage a good competition to push each other, we do not want to compromise each persons safety When one pushes themselves over the limit.  </p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c7eb0d_3a2b9c069c3c410898060ce1f14f85a3~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>
#FUN</strong></p>
<p>Here at Swim Preceptors, we are big on FUN!!! for our younger Preceptees, we, as Gen Z coaches understands and empathise with them that learning through fun is the best way for anyone to retain information and what they have learnt. At Swim Preceptors, we have a saying, “If you aren’t having, you ain’t doing it right”. </p>

<p>1 to 1 sessions allows the fun to take place, to the liking of each preceptee. As each preceptee reaches the different milestones in their journey of learning how to swim, we want them to have happy memories of how far they have come. </p>


<p><strong>COME JOIN US TODAY!
</strong></p>
<p>All in all, our advocacy for 1 to 1 lessons are preeched as in line with our mission and what we stand for as a Gen Z coorporation. <strong>
</strong></p>
<p>We want to bring forth a new way in teaching our preceptees the life skill of swimming. At the same time, letting them enjoy the process of it I’m a safe and fun manner. For those who are reading this and have not join us, don’t wait any longer! Come Join Us Now!</p>

<p>See you at the pool ;)</p>
<p>Swim Preceptors. </p>

<p><strong>FOR MORE INFORMATION......</strong></p>

<p>Do follow and check out our Instagram and Facebook page for information about us Swim Preceptors and about why we use certain unique technique to bring out each preceptees swimming potential to its fullest. </p>

<p>IG/FB : @swimpreceptors</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Learning the #SwimPreceptorsWay]]></title><description><![CDATA[For our Younger Preceptees, we incorporate games and fun activities in our lesson to get them to learn better as well as to spark an...]]></description><link>https://www.swimpreceptors.com/post/learning-the-swimpreceptorsway</link><guid isPermaLink="false">61c97fa66aa5cd00167cf4ee</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 15:01:47 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c7eb0d_86a2e1018496477a8aa5c06fa93a8f05~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>swimpreceptors</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For our Younger Preceptees, we incorporate games and fun activities in our lesson to get them to learn better as well as to spark an interest to learn how to swim. Come see what we do that made a Preceptee able to swim freestyle in just 3 lessons!</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c7eb0d_86a2e1018496477a8aa5c06fa93a8f05~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>IN PHOTO: Swim Preceptor, Coach Leo in action.</p>
<h3>why games & activities?</h3>
<p>We live in a world where each upcoming generation has its own unique way of picking up skills, using words and more important, its own unique way of learning new things. For our Younger Preceptees, they're learning process aligns with our Preceptors generation where most of us learn more effectively when we are having fun. </p>
<h3><strong>More Fun, More Learning!</strong></h3>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c7eb0d_6cc087c0dc684f248b767f8452568e1d~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p> As our Preceptors empathises with our Preceptees, we formulate our swimming lesson plan to cater the needs to each and every one of our preceptee to ensure effective and efficient learning. </p>

<p>An example would be like shown in the photo on the right where our preceptor uses underwater rings to challenges preceptees to take it from underwater. This mini game pushes preceptees to be more confident going to deeper waters as well as to blow bubbles underwater.</p>

<p>This also emphasises on Swim Preceptors view of private lessons and small group lessons. By keeping the group at a maximum of 3, we can watch out for our preceptees in the safety aspect, as well as to cater to each Preceptee to the best of our ability. #SwimPreceptorsWay</p>










]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[6 Months of Swim Preceptors]]></title><description><![CDATA[As we have embarked on this journey of changing the way the of teaching children and adults how to swim, we would like to thank all our...]]></description><link>https://www.swimpreceptors.com/post/6-months-of-swim-preceptors</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5fd81c4a2f0a50001740757c</guid><pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 02:15:38 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c7eb0d_8ce7d298b2b94aa0990bd5d2d78a3a58~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_853,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>swimpreceptors</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As we have embarked on this journey of changing the way the of teaching children and adults how to swim, we would like to thank all our clients for their unwavering support, as well as our preceptors who have tirelessly done their job in perfection.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/c7eb0d_8ce7d298b2b94aa0990bd5d2d78a3a58~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_853,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>From Left: <u>Co-Founder</u> <strong>Wong Wei Jer </strong>with <u>Co-Founder</u> <strong>Luke Chua</strong> </p>

<h2>The Launch of Swim Preceptors</h2><blockquote>“Swim Preceptors is our way of giving back to the community. We want to be able to give kids a new way of learning how to swim. As well as for our Gen Z coaches to acquire new skills that can help them in the future ”</blockquote>
<p>The thought of Swim preceptors came to Co-founder, Wong Wei jer in 2020 in which then launched the start of Swim preceptors in June 2021 with Co-founder Luke Chua. Swim Preceptors aims to help both Precep<strong>tors</strong> and Precep<strong>tee. </strong></p>

<p>The start of this 6 months might have been rocky, nevertheless, we are proud to have come this far living our everyday lives working towards this common go of giving the children of Singapore a new way if learning things.</p>

<h2>The Generation Z </h2>
<p>Our Preceptors is a team of passionate Gen Zs. With the hectic lifestyle of Gen Zs, we have found that many Gen Zs are actually working outside school to support themselves or earn an extra cash. Hence, in order to assist this group of Gen Zs, Swim Preceptors create an avenue where they can acquire new skills, give back to the community, and earn worthwhile money. </p>
<h2>From Us, to the Next </h2>
<p>Our Preceptees, for the young, with our ever increasing national education standards, there has been a lack exploration and time for our future generation to do something other than studying. At Swim Preceptors, we aim to give a holistic development for our preceptees, to be able to enjoy the learning process of swimming, as well as any other sport. </p>
<p>Along with our Gen Z coaches, we hope for the creative mindset and the mentality of our coaches to in still the fun in learning how to swim. It has often been said that, "When you are having fun, you will be more interested in learning". </p>
<h2>Special Needs </h2>
<p>At Swim preceptors, we believe that learning how to swim is an essential for everyone and that swimming can help special needs kids. Learning how to swim can be a source of therapy and an engaging tool for special needs to be equipped with. We are always welcoming for anyone who wants to learn swimming the #swimpreceptorsway :)</p>

<p> </p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>